Benjamin Vaughan Papers 1746-1900 Mss.B.V46p
American Philosophical Society
Benjamin Vaughan Papers
1746-1900
Mss.B.V46p
American Philosophical Society
13.25 Linear feet
Letters (including some transcripts and photostats) from and to Vaughan from many American and British correspondents, including: Also personal correspondence and business papers of Benjamin, Charles, Petty, Samuel Sr., Samuel Jr., William, William Oliver, and Sarah Vaughan (2 boxes); lectures, mostly in shorthand (3 vols.); a large number of notes and memoranda on a wide variety of topics, such as agriculture, architecture, astronomy, diplomacy, diseases, dueling, electricity, hieroglyphs, internal improvements, medicine, meteorology, land, manufactures, politics, punctuation, religion, silk-manufacturing, stock-breeding, taxation, Unitarianism, Benjamin Franklin, John Locke, Napoleon I, Joseph Priestley, Bowdoin College, town of Hallowell, Maine; notes on the peace negotiations, 1782-1783; miscellaneous legal papers; genealogy of the Abbott-Vaughan families. For a personal account of the collection, see Mrs. Mary Vaughan Marvin, "The Benjamin Vaughan Papers," APS Proceedings 95 (1951): 246-249.
Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
Bibliography
Murray C. Craig, Benjamin Vaughan (1751-1835): The Life of an Anglo-American Intellectual (NY: Arno Press, 1982).
Mary Vaughan Marvin, "The Benjamin Vaughan Papers," American Philosophical Society Proceedings 95 (1951): 246-249.
African American History Note
This collection contains at least one item which may be of interest to students of African American history: a manuscript concerning slaves in the British West Indies, entitled "Negroes."
Early American History Note
The Benjamin Vaughan Papers contain an extensive amount of correspondence and other documents. MOLE contains a detailed inventory of its holdings. Vaughan was a prominent figure in the revolutionary Atlantic. This large collection captures the complex and high profile life Benjamin led. He was born in the Caribbean but grew up in London. He became a friend of Franklin and his circle in London in the 1770s. During the War for Independence, he served as an emissary to the peace negotiations between the U.S. and British. He then spent a few years in Switzerland before emigrating to the United States with his wife. They settled in Maine, where Vaughan dabbled in speculation, farming, and other pursuits. His brother John became active in the American Philosophical Society.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Acquired from Mary Vaughan Marvin and others, 1950-1995.
Scope and Contents note
The Vaughan Papers contains a substantial representation of the voluminous correspondence and writings of Benjamin Vaughan, focussed on his relationship with the Earl of Shelburne, Benjamin Franklin, and other members of the Vaughan Family. Consisting primarily of manuscript letters received by Vaughan, typescript copies of letters to him, and incidental essays, notes, financial papers, and legal documents, the collection is particularly strong in documenting Vaughan's life just prior to his emigration to America through until his death.
Series I Correspondence with John Vaughan, 1780-1819 (40 items; 0.25 linear feet)
Series II General correspondence, 1746-1952 (26 boxes; 6.5 linear feet)
Series III Manuscripts (3 boxes; 0.75 linear feet)
Series IV Subject files (11 boxes, 2.75 linear feet)
Series V Bound volumes (24 items; 3 linear feet)
Biographical/Historical note
Benjamin Vaughan lived through all the vicissitudes of an enlightened life during the age of revolution. Born in Jamaica to Samuel Vaughan, a merchant and planter, and Sarah Hallowell, a native Bostonian, Vaughan was raised in London and educated at Cambridge and Lincoln's Inn. At university, he fell in with the coterie of Joseph Priestley, Benjamin Franklin, Jeremy Bentham, and William Petty, the Earl of Shelburne, and imbibed many of their unorthodox, perhaps radical political, social, and religious views. Whether a product of his own colonial origins or his contact with Franklin, Priestley, and Price, Vaughan took a particularly keen interest in American affairs, advocating reconciliation throughout the Revolutionary conflict. In 1783, as a result of his connections to then-Prime Minister Shelburne and his association with Franklin (having seen to the English publication of the first volume of Franklin's political writings), Vaughan was dispatched to Paris to mollify Franklin and the American negotiators and assure them of good English intentions. Although he was barred as a dissenter from any official role in the negotiations, Vaughan played an important unofficial role in quickening the closure of the treaty and the formalization and recognition of American independence.
As Vaughan's political and diplomatic star was rising, his improbable pursuit of the hand of Sarah Manning, the daughter of an ardent Tory, led him to study medicine in Edinburgh to establish his name as a reputable suitor. Although he never completed his studies, he did marry Sarah in 1781, joining her father's mercantile business shortly thereafter, and he maintained an active interest in medical affairs for much of the remainder of his life. He remained loyal to Shelburne after Shelburne's departure from the ministry in 1784, and was elected to represent Calne in Parliament in 1793. However in the backlash against republicanism, Vaughan's political views and his sympathy for the French Revolution conspired to make him obnoxious to the majority of the government, if not the people, and when war with France erupted in February, 1793, he began to feel the heat. As a result, when called before the Privy Council in May, 1794, he decided that flight was the better part of valor and took off for America, where his popularity was undiminished, by way of France. Ironically, as a foreign national arriving in Paris during the most radical phase of the Revolution, he was immediately arrested and imprisoned. Released in July, Vaughan remained in Switzerland and France for over three years before receiving a passport to join his wife and children in the United States.
Settling on family lands in the nether reaches of Hallowell, Maine, Vaughan worked his land, speculated (like many of his contemporaries) in real estate, and maintained an active correspondence with his wide circle of intellectual acquaintances, including his brother John long-time Librarian of the American Philosophical Society. In this remote outpost, he amassed one of the largest private libraries in New England, almost 12,000 volumes, and continued to take part in political discussions with American officials at the highest level, though he never again held elective office. A committed Federalist and a proponent of harmonious relations between England and America, he was a vocal critic of the War of 1812 and his social and political philosophy led him consistently to oppose American westward and southward expansion. Vaughan died in 1835.
Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848; Allen, William, 1770-1843; Appleton, Jesse, 1772-1819; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858; Dexter, Aaron; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790; Freeman, James, 1759-1835; Gardiner, Robert Hallowell, 1782-1864; Locke, John, 1632-1704; Manning, William, 1767-1849; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831; Napoleon I, Emperor of the French, 1769-1821; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813; Snow, Gideon,; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866; Vaughan, Charles, 1759-1839; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854; Vaughan, Samuel, 1762-1827; Vaughan, Samuel, Sr., 1720-1802; Vaughan, Sarah; Vaughan, William Oliver, 1783-1826; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856; Agriculture; American Revolution; Animal magnetism.; Architecture; Astronomy; Beyond Early America; Bowdoin College; Breeding.; Colonial Politics; Diplomacy.; Diplomatic History; Diplomatic Material; Diseases; Dueling.; Early National Politics; Electricity; Family Correspondence; Genealogies; General Correspondence; Hallowell (Me.); Land and Speculation; Lectures; Manufactures; Maps and Surveys; Medicine; Mesmerism; Meteorology; Notes; Plantations; Punctuation; Religion; Science and Technology; Silk industry.; Slaves, slavery, slave trade; Taxation; Unitarianism; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783
- Series I. Correspondence with John Vaughan, 1780-1819; 40 items, 0.25 linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Manuscript letters from Benjamin Vaughan, to his brother, John, arranged in two chronological series.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 15, 1777; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    [London] A.L.S. 5p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.25.) Is concerned about their father. Advises leaving (?) Jamaica; brotherly advice on John's conduct.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 22, 1778; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    [London] A.L. 4p., add. (see his letters to John Vaughan, no.26) Looks "upon war as too certain." "The prevailing opinion among public men is in favor of an acknowledged independence." Brotherly advice.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 20, 1780; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    [London] A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.1) Introduces Mr. Barry. John's situation at Bordeaux. Goes to Edinburgh to attend lectures on anatomy, etc. Jamaica.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 16, 1782; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no. 27) Introduces Moses Young, secretary to Mr. Laurens.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 7, 1784; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L. 5p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.28) Slowness in pay on part of American business men detriment to trade. John's business transactions.
  - Letter to John [Vaughan], Sept. 23, 1784; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 7p. and end. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.29) Advice - business and marital.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 2, 1788; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.2) Comments on Mr. Rumsey's invention. John Vaughan's bad financial transactions. References to Dr. Franklin.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 1, 1789; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.3) News from America includes the proposition of a colony under Spanish protection towards the mouth of the Mississippi - comments on. Enclosure for Dr. Franklin.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 6, 1789; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.4) Insects infecting American corn; resulting trade restrictions; Hessian fly. Order for American journals. Mentions Sir Joseph Banks, Joseph Priestley, B. Franklin, and others.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 29, 1789; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.30) The French revolution; European politics.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 17, 1789; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 4p., add. (see His Letters to John Vaughan, no.31.) Business advice.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 4, 1791; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.5) Introduces the Earl of Wycombe, the bearer of this letter.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 6, 1791; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.32) Credit for the Earl of Wycombe.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 9, 1791; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London. A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.6) Ld. Wycombe goes to America. European politics. Order for recent books and magazines for Sir Joseph Banks and himself
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 29, 1792; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.7) Introduces Mr. Charles Wollstonecraft. (Contains autograph of C. Wollstonecraft)
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 6, 1792; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L. 2p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.8) Possibility of procuring an establishment for some of the French refugee clergy on his father's land in Pennsylvania. Plans for house. Asks that he consult with Mr. Jefferson and others. English and French politics.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 5, 1793; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.9) Introduces Mr. James Redman. Mentions Dr. Priestley. (Contains autograph of James Redman)
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 4, 1793; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.10) Encloses mail from Mme. de Cocherel to be forwarded to her husband. French affairs.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 10, 1793; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.33) Introduces Dr. James Mackittrick Adair.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 10, 1793; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.11) Introduces Mrs. D'Arch who plans to settle in America with her three daughters
  - Letter to John Vaughan [or Charles Vaughan], Oct. 7, 1794; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Berne, A.L.S. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.34) American investments for David Rodolf Fellenberg of Berne. Contains an"obligation" signed by David (?) Fellenberg and Ph. Em. Fellenberg.
  - Letter to his brothers, John [and Charles Vaughan], Oct. 20, 1794; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Basle, A.L.S. 2p. and end. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.35) Business for Messrs. Fellenberg.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 27, 1799; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.12) Comments upon [Dr. Priestley] and his publications. Personal matters - transfer to lands, receipt of books, sheep raising, etc. Work by Arthur Young.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 17, 1801; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.13) Innoculation; infected cattle; mentions Drs. Jenner, Waterhouse, Jackson, Rush, J. R. Coxe, and Mr. Jefferson. Attacks of the fever. Is too busy to prepare paper for the Philosophical society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 30, 1802; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.14) Land transactions. Water purifying apparatus. St. Domingo; Toussaint.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 8, 1802; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 3p. and add. (see his letters to John Vaughan, no.15) Books. West Indies. Bonaparte.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 1,3, 1803; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.16) Desires books on mills; plans to build one. French situation; Bonaparte.
  - Letter to John Vaughan [Hallowell,], August, 1804; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    A.L. 8p., add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.37) Transcribes a letter by J.J. Rousseau in re Hirzel and the "Rural Socrates." Biographical data on Dr. Priestley. B[onaparte] and European politics.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 1, 1804; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.17) Death of Dr. Priestley. Surveying a certain township. Melon seeds.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 31, 1804; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p., add. Seal. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no. 36) Description of a grist mill he is building. B[onaparte] and European politics. Louisiana. Klyogg [Rural Socrates].
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 12, 1804; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.18) Biographical data about Joseph Priestley.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 16, 1804; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.19) Orders for books. Elections. Dr. Priestley.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 14, 1806; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L.S. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.20) Various books. Faculty of Harvard; possibility of the establishment of a medical school there. Theological controversy. Suggests American edition of Chambaud's French dictionary.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 29, 1807; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.21) Orders for various articles. Extreme cold weather. Experiments in freezing quicksilver.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 28, 1807; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L.S. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.22) Is introducing grapes; orders cuttings; hopes to send a treatise on their cultivation. Recommends White's Compendium of the veterinary art to Dr. Rush; suggests compilation of some similar work in America, possibly by Dr. Mease (?). Bonaparte.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 19, 1807; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 4p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan,no.23) All of Dr. Rush's works sold. Calomel now established through country. Severe cold; effect of on the body; blood heat. Account of cold may be reported to the [Philosophical] Society.
  - Letter to his brother [John Vaughan], April 16, 1808; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 2p. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.38) Relative to an account of an extraordinary flight of meteors described by Andrew Ellicot in the APS Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 13, 1809; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 2p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.24) Their estates [in Jamaica]. Bonaparte.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 23, 1819; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.39) Relative to an invention of Mr. [Jacob ?] Perkins.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 20, 1819; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, A.L.S. 3p. and add. (see his Letters to John Vaughan, no.40) Information about Mr. [Jacob ?] P[erkins].
- Series II. General Correspondence, 1746-1952; 6.5 linear feet (Box 2-27)
  Manuscript letters to and from Benjamin Vaughan, arranged chronologically, with particularly rich correspondence with Franklin, Shelburne, and members of the Vaughan family, as well as a small number of ancillary documents and correspondence relating to financial and estate matters. A number of items from the period before 1790 are typescript copies of originals held in other institutions or in private hands.
  After about 1798, the correspondence is largely confined to members of the family, particularly Charles, William, Petty, and Sarah Vaughan. While some of the family correspondence is inevitably consumed with financial and other family matters, the full range of Vaughan's interests emerges, including his political, social, scientific, and familial concerns. A grasping intellect, Vaughan had a through grounding in philosophical and religious issues, but he had a strong interest as well in useful, applied knowledge. As such, his correspondence runs both toward the theoretical -- on moral philosophy, political theory, religious doctrine, or scientific schemes -- and the practical from bridges to diseases, taxation, animal husbandry, agriculture, internal improvements, medical practice, and political practice.
  The general correspondence series includes a few essays and sets of notes on topical issues, including English foreign policy (ca. 1792), relations with France (ca. 1792), slavery (ca. 1792), and yellow fever (1795), and in the undated materials, items relating to the last illness and death of Joseph Priestley, fire engines, inoculation, and various mechanical inventions. The majority of such manuscripts have been separated into Series III.
  Among the better known correspondents are Benjamin Franklin, the Earl of Shelburne, Joseph Priestley, Thomas Jefferson, and Parker Cleaveland.
  - LS to Mr. Baxter, [1746]; 7 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin's observations on Mr. Baxter's book.
  - LS to [Huey, Joseph], 1753 June 6; 3 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    A letter thanking Joseph Huey for his kindness.
  - ADS, 1765 October 24; 2 p.; Hancock, John, 1737-1793
    Joseph and Samuel Warren indenture to John Hancock for 133 pounds.
  - ALS to [?], 1766 January 6; 5 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - ALS to [?], [ca. 1767]; 10 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Remarks and notes on the benefits of paper money in the Unites States.
    General note
    First and second page missing.
  - MsS, [ca. 1769]; 3 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - ALS toVaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835 and Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802, 1773 January 16; 4 p.; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Mr. Norgate died. Explains the use of fractions.
    Notes written by someone other than John Vaughan at end of letter.
  - ALS to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1773 Septmeber 15; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, [1773] September 21; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Gives John advice and suggestions for a piece that he is writing.
  - ALS to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1773 September 22; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1773 September 27, October 7; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AL to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1773 October 11; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AL to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1773 October 14; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AL to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1773 November 8; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Gives John advice and suggestions for a piece that he is writing. Requests that John send him his papers.
  - AMs, 1773 December 16 - 1776 August 29; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Chronology of event leading up to the American Revolution.
  - TLS Cy Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1776 December 29; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan enclosed "some papers for perusal" that are missing.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1777 January 24; 1 p.; Oliver, Richard,
    Oliver asks Vaughan for new about America.
  - LS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1777 September 18; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin requests to meet with Vaughan at the bath.
  - Vaughan, Charles, 1759-1839, 1777 October 24; 16 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Letter of advice to younger brother embarking for Jamaica.
  - ALS to Ben H, 1778; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Letter is housed with 1777 October 24. Letter of advice to his cousin about to embark to the East Indies.
  - TLS Cy Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1778 April 14; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - LS to Comte de St. Germaine [?], 1778 November 12; 2 p.; Duportail, Antoine-Jean-Louis Le Begue de Presle, 1743-1802
    Translation of letter.
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1779 May 5; 2 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin discusses his writings and papers.
  - AL to Reverend Wood, 1779 June 9; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan asks Rev. Wood to join the Society as Minister.
  - ALS to [Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835], 1779 June; 1 p.; [Wood, Reverend]
    Rev. Wood declines Vaughans offer to preach but would like to meet with him.
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1779 November 9; 3 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Vaughan is in charge of some editing of Franklin's papers
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802 and son, 1779 November 9; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Short note.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1779 November 23; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, [1779]; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan is editing some of Franklin's papers